Resources

Privacy Policy of **short.io**
==============================

Short.io collects some Personal Data from its Users.

Users may be subject to different protection standards and broader standards may therefore apply to some. Users can contact the Owner, to learn more about such standards.

This document can be printed for reference by using the print command in the settings of any browser.

Owner and Data Controller
-------------------------

Short.cm

**Owner contact email:** support@short.io

Types of Data collected
-----------------------

Among the types of Personal Data that short.io collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: email address; Usage Data; Cookies; number of Users; session statistics; password; IP address; device information; browser information; operating systems; city; ZIP/Postal code; state; county; country; latitude (of city); longitude (of city); metro area; geography/region; answers to questions; Data communicated in order to use the Service; session duration; Application opens; launches; Data communicated while using the service.

Complete details on each type of Personal Data collected are provided in the dedicated sections of this privacy policy or by specific explanation texts displayed prior to the Data collection.  
Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or, in case of Usage Data, collected automatically when using short.io.  
Unless specified otherwise, all Data requested by short.io is mandatory and failure to provide this Data may make it impossible for short.io to provide its services. In cases where short.io specifically states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to communicate this Data without consequences to the availability or the functioning of the Service.  
Users who are uncertain about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact the Owner.  
Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools — by short.io or by the owners of third-party services used by short.io serves the purpose of providing the Service required by the User, in addition to any other purposes described in the present document and in the Cookie Policy.

Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through short.io.

Mode and place of processing the Data
-------------------------------------

### Methods of processing

The Owner takes appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.  
The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Owner, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of short.io (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third-party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Owner at any time.

### Place

The Data is processed at the Owner's operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved in the processing are located.  
  
Depending on the User's location, data transfers may involve transferring the User's Data to a country other than their own. To find out more about the place of processing of such transferred Data, Users can check the section containing details about the processing of Personal Data.

### Retention time

Unless specified otherwise in this document, Personal Data shall be processed and stored for as long as required by the purpose they have been collected for and may be retained for longer due to applicable legal obligation or based on the Users’ consent.

The purposes of processing
--------------------------

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its Service, comply with its legal obligations, respond to enforcement requests, protect its rights and interests (or those of its Users or third parties), detect any malicious or fraudulent activity, as well as the following: Handling payments, Hosting and backend infrastructure, Managing contacts and sending messages, Tag Management, Heat mapping and session recording, Infrastructure monitoring, Remarketing and behavioral targeting, Advertising, Registration and authentication, User database management, Interaction with support and feedback platforms, Analytics, Registration and authentication provided directly by short.io, Traffic optimization and distribution and Spam and bots protection.

For specific information about the Personal Data used for each purpose, the User may refer to the section “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data”.

Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data
-------------------------------------------------------

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

* ### Advertising
    
    This type of service allows User Data to be utilized for advertising communication purposes. These communications are displayed in the form of banners and other advertisements on short.io, possibly based on User interests.  
    This does not mean that all Personal Data are used for this purpose. Information and conditions of use are shown below.  
    Some of the services listed below may use Trackers for identifying Users, behavioral retargeting i.e. displaying ads tailored to the User’s interests and behavior, or to measure ads performance. For more information, please check the privacy policies of the relevant services.  
    Services of this kind usually offer the possibility to opt out of such tracking. In addition to any opt-out feature offered by any of the services below, Users may learn more on how to generally opt out of interest-based advertising within the dedicated section "How to opt-out of interest-based advertising" in this document.
    
    #### Google Ads conversion tracking (Google Inc.)
    
    Google Ads conversion tracking is an analytics service provided by Google LLC or by Google Ireland Limited, depending on how the Owner manages the Data processing, that connects data from the Google Ads advertising network with actions performed on short.io.
    
    Personal Data processed: Trackers; Usage Data.
    
    Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).
    
* ### Analytics
    
    The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.
    
    #### Google Analytics 4
    
    Google Analytics 4 is a web analysis service provided by Google LLC or by Google Ireland Limited, depending on how the Owner manages the Data processing, (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of short.io, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.  
    Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.  
    In Google Analytics 4, IP addresses are used at collection time and then discarded before Data is logged in any data center or server. Users can learn more by consulting [Google’s official documentation](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/12017362?hl=en&ref_topic=2919631).
    
    In order to understand Google's use of Data, consult [Google's partner policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).
    
    Personal Data processed: number of Users; session statistics; Trackers; Usage Data.
    
    Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://business.safety.google/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en); Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://business.safety.google/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).
    
    #### Google Analytics for Firebase (for apps)
    
    Google Analytics for Firebase (for apps) or Firebase Analytics is an analytics service provided by Google LLC or by Google Ireland Limited, depending on how the Owner manages the Data processing. **In order to understand Google's use of Data, consult [Google's partner policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/)**.
    
    Firebase Analytics may share Data with other tools provided by Firebase, such as Crash Reporting, Authentication, Remote Config or Notifications. The User may check this privacy policy to find a detailed explanation about the other tools used by the Owner.
    
    Short.io uses identifiers for mobile devices and technologies similar to cookies to run the Firebase Analytics service.
    
    Users may opt-out of certain Firebase features through applicable device settings, such as the device advertising settings for mobile phones or by following the instructions in other Firebase related sections of this privacy policy, if available.
    
    Personal Data processed: Application opens; launches; session duration.
    
    Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://business.safety.google/privacy/); Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://business.safety.google/privacy/).
    
* ### Handling payments
    
    Payment processing services enable short.io to process payments by credit card, bank transfer or other means. To ensure greater security, short.io shares only the information necessary to execute the transaction with the financial intermediaries handling the transaction.  
    Some of these services may also enable the sending of timed messages to the User, such as emails containing invoices or notifications concerning the payment.
    
    #### Stripe (Stripe Inc)
    
    Stripe is a payment service provided by Stripe Inc.
    
    Personal Data processed: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
    
    Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/terms/US).
    
* ### Heat mapping and session recording
    
    Heat Mapping services are used to display the areas of a page where Users most frequently move the mouse or click. This shows where the points of interest are. These services make it possible to monitor and analyze web traffic and keep track of User behavior.  
    Some of these services may record sessions and make them available for later visual playback.
    
    #### Hotjar Heat Maps & Recordings (Hotjar Ltd.)
    
    Hotjar is a session recording and heat mapping service provided by Hotjar Ltd.  
    Hotjar honors generic „Do Not Track” headers. This means the browser can tell its script not to collect any of the User's data. This is a setting that is available in all major browsers. Find Hotjar’s [opt-out information here](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out).
    
    Personal Data processed: Cookies; Usage Data; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
    
    Place of processing: Malta – [Privacy Policy](https://www.hotjar.com/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out).
    
* ### Hosting and backend infrastructure
    
    This type of service has the purpose of hosting Data and files that enable short.io to run and be distributed as well as to provide a ready-made infrastructure to run specific features or parts of short.io. Some of these services work through geographically distributed servers, making it difficult to determine the actual location where the Personal Data are stored.
    
    #### Amazon Web Services (AWS) (Amazon)
    
    Amazon Web Services (AWS) is a hosting and backend service provided by Amazon Web Services, Inc.
    
    Personal Data processed: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
    
    Place of processing: See the Amazon privacy policy – [Privacy Policy](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/).
    
    #### OpenAI API (OpenAI, L.L.C.)
    
    The OpenAI API provided by OpenAI, L.L.C. is a service that helps the Owner to automate tasks through its AI engine.
    
    Personal Data processed: Data communicated while using the service.
    
    Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://openai.com/policies/privacy-policy).
    
* ### Infrastructure monitoring
    
    This type of service allows short.io to monitor the use and behavior of its components so its performance, operation, maintenance and troubleshooting can be improved.  
    Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and mode of implementation of these services, whose function is to filter the activities of short.io.
    
    #### Sentry (GetSentry, LLC)
    
    Sentry is a monitoring service provided by Functional Software, Inc. .
    
    Personal Data processed: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
    
    Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.getsentry.com/privacy/).
    
    #### Statuspage.io
    
    We display a notification message if our service is down
    
* ### Interaction with support and feedback platforms
    
    This type of service allows Users to interact with third-party support and feedback platforms directly from the pages of short.io.  
    If one of these services is installed, it may collect browsing and Usage Data in the pages where it is installed, even if the Users do not actively use the service.
    
    #### Canny
    
    We display changelog from this service
    
* ### Managing contacts and sending messages
    
    This type of service makes it possible to manage a database of email contacts, phone contacts or any other contact information to communicate with the User.  
    These services may also collect data concerning the date and time when the message was viewed by the User, as well as when the User interacted with it, such as by clicking on links included in the message.
    
    #### Amazon Simple Email Service (Amazon)
    
    Amazon Simple Email Service is an email address management and message sending service provided by Amazon.com Inc.
    
    Personal Data processed: email address.
    
    Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/data-privacy-faq/).
    
* ### Registration and authentication
    
    By registering or authenticating, Users allow short.io to identify them and give them access to dedicated services.  
    Depending on what is described below, third parties may provide registration and authentication services. In this case, short.io will be able to access some Data, stored by these third-party services, for registration or identification purposes.
    
    #### Google OAuth (Google Inc.)
    
    Google OAuth is a registration and authentication service provided by Google Inc. and is connected to the Google network.
    
    Personal Data processed: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
    
    Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).
    
    #### Facebook Authentication (Meta Platforms, Inc.)
    
    Facebook Authentication is a registration and authentication service provided by Meta Platforms, Inc. and is connected to the Facebook social network.
    
    Personal Data processed: Trackers; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
    
    Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/help/405977429438260).
    
* ### Registration and authentication provided directly by short.io
    
    By registering or authenticating, Users allow short.io to identify them and give them access to dedicated services. The Personal Data is collected and stored for registration or identification purposes only. The Data collected are only those necessary for the provision of the service requested by the Users.
    
    #### Direct registration (short.io)
    
    The User registers by filling out the registration form and providing the Personal Data directly to short.io.
    
    Personal Data processed: email address; password.
    
* ### Remarketing and behavioral targeting
    
    This type of service allows short.io and its partners to inform, optimize and serve advertising based on past use of short.io by the User.  
    This activity is facilitated by tracking Usage Data and by using Trackers to collect information which is then transferred to the partners that manage the remarketing and behavioral targeting activity.  
    Some services offer a remarketing option based on email address lists.  
    In addition to any opt-out feature provided by any of the services below, Users may opt out by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1).
    
    **Users may also opt-out of certain advertising features through applicable device settings, such as the device advertising settings for mobile phones or ads settings in general**.
    
    #### Google Ads Remarketing (Google Inc.)
    
    Google Ads Remarketing is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Google LLC or by Google Ireland Limited, depending on how the Owner manages the Data processing, that connects the activity of short.io with the Google Ads advertising network and the DoubleClick Cookie.
    
    Users can opt out of Google's use of cookies for ads personalization by visiting Google's [Ads Settings](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated).
    
    Personal Data processed: Cookies; Usage Data.
    
    Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout).
    
* ### Spam and bots protection
    
    This type of service analyzes the traffic of short.io, potentially containing Users' Personal Data, with the purpose of filtering it from unwanted parts of traffic, messages and content that are recognized as spam or protecting it from malicious bots activities.
    
    #### hCaptcha (Intuition Machines, Inc)
    
    hCaptcha is a SPAM protection service provided by Intuition Machines, Inc.
    
    Personal Data processed: answers to questions; Data communicated in order to use the Service.
    
    Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.hcaptcha.com/privacy).
    
* ### Tag Management
    
    This type of service helps the Owner to manage the tags or scripts needed on short.io in a centralized fashion.  
    This results in the Users' Data flowing through these services, potentially resulting in the retention of this Data.
    
    #### Google Tag Manager (Google LLC)
    
    Google Tag Manager is a tag management service provided by Google LLC or by Google Ireland Limited, depending on how the Owner manages the Data processing.
    
    Personal Data processed: Usage Data.
    
    Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).
    
* ### Traffic optimization and distribution
    
    This type of service allows short.io to distribute their content using servers located across different countries and to optimize their performance.  
    Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and the way these services are implemented. Their function is to filter communications between short.io and the User's browser.  
    Considering the widespread distribution of this system, it is difficult to determine the locations to which the contents that may contain Personal Information of the User are transferred.
    
    #### Amazon CloudFront (Amazon Web Services, Inc.)
    
    Amazon CloudFront is a traffic optimization and distribution service provided by Amazon Web Services, Inc.
    
    Personal Data processed: browser information; city; country; county; device information; geography/region; IP address; latitude (of city); longitude (of city); metro area; operating systems; state; Usage Data; ZIP/Postal code.
    
    Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/); Australia – [Privacy Policy](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/); Germany – [Privacy Policy](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/).
    
* ### User database management
    
    This type of service allows the Owner to build user profiles by starting from an email address, a personal name, or other information that the User provides to short.io, as well as to track User activities through analytics features. This Personal Data may also be matched with publicly available information about the User (such as social networks' profiles) and used to build private profiles that the Owner can display and use for improving short.io.  
    Some of these services may also enable the sending of timed messages to the User, such as emails based on specific actions performed on short.io.
    
    #### Intercom (Intercom Inc.)
    
    Intercom is a User database management service provided by Intercom Inc. Intercom can also be used as a medium for communications, either through email, or through messages within short.io.
    
    Personal Data processed: Cookies; email address; Usage Data; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
    
    Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#privacy).

Information on opting out of interest-based advertising
-------------------------------------------------------

In addition to any opt-out feature provided by any of the services listed in this document, Users may learn more on how to generally opt out of interest-based advertising within the dedicated section of the Cookie Policy.

Cookie Policy
-------------

Short.io uses Trackers. To learn more, Users may consult the [Cookie Policy](https://www.iubenda.com/private/privacy-policy/1126577/cookie-policy "Cookie Policy").

Further Information for Users in the European Union
---------------------------------------------------

This section applies to all Users in the European Union, according to the General Data Protection Regulation (the “GDPR”), and, for such Users, supersedes any other possibly divergent or conflicting information contained in the privacy policy. Further details regarding the categories of Data processed, the purposes of processing, the categories of recipients of the Personal Data, if any, and further information about Personal Data can be found in **the section titled “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document**.

### Legal basis of processing

The Owner may process Personal Data relating to Users if one of the following applies:

* Users have given their consent for one or more specific purposes.
* provision of Data is necessary for the performance of an agreement with the User and/or for any pre-contractual obligations thereof;
* processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which the Owner is subject;
* processing is related to a task that is carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the Owner;
* processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner or by a third party.

In any case, the Owner will gladly help to clarify the specific legal basis that applies to the processing, and in particular whether the provision of Personal Data is a statutory or contractual requirement, or a requirement necessary to enter into a contract.

### Further information about retention time

Unless specified otherwise in this document, Personal Data shall be processed and stored for as long as required by the purpose they have been collected for and may be retained for longer due to applicable legal obligation or based on the Users’ consent.

Therefore:

* Personal Data collected for purposes related to the performance of a contract between the Owner and the User shall be retained until such contract has been fully performed.
* Personal Data collected for the purposes of the Owner’s legitimate interests shall be retained as long as needed to fulfill such purposes. Users may find specific information regarding the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner within the relevant sections of this document or by contacting the Owner.

The Owner may be allowed to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever the User has given consent to such processing, as long as such consent is not withdrawn. Furthermore, the Owner may be obliged to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever required to fulfil a legal obligation or upon order of an authority.  
  
Once the retention period expires, Personal Data shall be deleted. Therefore, the right of access, the right to erasure, the right to rectification and the right to data portability cannot be enforced after expiration of the retention period.

### The rights of Users based on the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

Users may exercise certain rights regarding their Data processed by the Owner.

In particular, Users have the right to do the following, to the extent permitted by law:

* **Withdraw their consent at any time.** Users have the right to withdraw consent where they have previously given their consent to the processing of their Personal Data.
* **Object to processing of their Data.** Users have the right to object to the processing of their Data if the processing is carried out on a legal basis other than consent.
* **Access their Data.** Users have the right to learn if Data is being processed by the Owner, obtain disclosure regarding certain aspects of the processing and obtain a copy of the Data undergoing processing.
* **Verify and seek rectification.** Users have the right to verify the accuracy of their Data and ask for it to be updated or corrected.
* **Restrict the processing of their Data.** Users have the right to restrict the processing of their Data. In this case, the Owner will not process their Data for any purpose other than storing it.
* **Have their Personal Data deleted or otherwise removed.** Users have the right to obtain the erasure of their Data from the Owner.
* **Receive their Data and have it transferred to another controller.** Users have the right to receive their Data in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format and, if technically feasible, to have it transmitted to another controller without any hindrance.
* **Lodge a complaint.** Users have the right to bring a claim before their competent data protection authority.

Users are also entitled to learn about the legal basis for Data transfers abroad including to any international organization governed by public international law or set up by two or more countries, such as the UN, and about the security measures taken by the Owner to safeguard their Data.

#### Details about the right to object to processing

**Where Personal Data is processed for a public interest, in the exercise of an official authority vested in the Owner or for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner, Users may object to such processing by providing a ground related to their particular situation to justify the objection.**

**Users must know that, however, should their Personal Data be processed for direct marketing purposes, they can object to that processing at any time, free of charge and without providing any justification. Where the User objects to processing for direct marketing purposes, the Personal Data will no longer be processed for such purposes. To learn whether the Owner is processing Personal Data for direct marketing purposes, Users may refer to the relevant sections of this document.**

#### How to exercise these rights

Any requests to exercise User rights can be directed to the Owner through the contact details provided in this document. Such requests are free of charge and will be answered by the Owner as early as possible and always within one month, providing Users with the information required by law. Any rectification or erasure of Personal Data or restriction of processing will be communicated by the Owner to each recipient, if any, to whom the Personal Data has been disclosed unless this proves impossible or involves disproportionate effort. At the Users’ request, the Owner will inform them about those recipients.

Additional information about Data collection and processing
-----------------------------------------------------------

### Legal action

The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Owner in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of short.io or the related Services.  
The User declares to be aware that the Owner may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities.

### Additional information about User's Personal Data

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, short.io may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular Services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request.

### System logs and maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, short.io and any third-party services may collect files that record interaction with short.io (System logs) or use other Personal Data (such as the IP Address) for this purpose.

### Information not contained in this policy

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Owner at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document.

### Changes to this privacy policy

The Owner reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by notifying its Users on this page and possibly within short.io and/or - as far as technically and legally feasible - sending a notice to Users via any contact information available to the Owner. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom.  
  
Should the changes affect processing activities performed on the basis of the User’s consent, the Owner shall collect new consent from the User, where required.

### Definitions and legal references

#### Personal Data (or Data)

Any information that directly, indirectly, or in connection with other information — including a personal identification number — allows for the identification or identifiability of a natural person.

#### Usage Data

Information collected automatically through short.io (or third-party services employed in short.io), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use short.io, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server's answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User's IT environment.

#### User

The individual using short.io who, unless otherwise specified, coincides with the Data Subject.

#### Data Subject

The natural person to whom the Personal Data refers.

#### Data Processor (or Processor)

The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which processes Personal Data on behalf of the Controller, as described in this privacy policy.

#### Data Controller (or Owner)

The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the processing of Personal Data, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of short.io. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of short.io.

#### short.io (or this Application)

The means by which the Personal Data of the User is collected and processed.

#### Service

The service provided by short.io as described in the relative terms (if available) and on this site/application.

#### European Union (or EU)

Unless otherwise specified, all references made within this document to the European Union include all current member states to the European Union and the European Economic Area.

#### Cookie

Cookies are Trackers consisting of small sets of data stored in the User's browser.

#### Tracker

Tracker indicates any technology - e.g Cookies, unique identifiers, web beacons, embedded scripts, e-tags and fingerprinting - that enables the tracking of Users, for example by accessing or storing information on the User’s device.

* * *

#### Legal information

This privacy policy relates solely to short.io, if not stated otherwise within this document.

Latest update: December 03, 2024

Cookie Policy of short.io
-------------------------

This document informs Users about the technologies that help short.io to achieve the purposes described below. Such technologies allow the Owner to access and store information (for example by using a Cookie) or use resources (for example by running a script) on a User’s device as they interact with short.io.

For simplicity, all such technologies are defined as "Trackers" within this document – unless there is a reason to differentiate.  
For example, while Cookies can be used on both web and mobile browsers, it would be inaccurate to talk about Cookies in the context of mobile apps as they are a browser-based Tracker. For this reason, within this document, the term Cookies is only used where it is specifically meant to indicate that particular type of Tracker.

Some of the purposes for which Trackers are used may also require the User's consent, depending on the applicable law. Whenever consent is given, it can be freely withdrawn at any time following the instructions provided in this document.

Short.io uses Trackers managed directly by the Owner (so-called “first-party” Trackers) and Trackers that enable services provided by a third-party (so-called “third-party” Trackers). Unless otherwise specified within this document, third-party providers may access the Trackers managed by them.  
The validity and expiration periods of Cookies and other similar Trackers may vary depending on the lifetime set by the Owner or the relevant provider. Some of them expire upon termination of the User’s browsing session.  
In addition to what’s specified in the descriptions within each of the categories below, Users may find more precise and updated information regarding lifetime specification as well as any other relevant information — such as the presence of other Trackers — in the linked privacy policies of the respective third-party providers or by contacting the Owner.

How short.io uses Trackers
--------------------------

### Necessary

Short.io uses so-called “technical” Cookies and other similar Trackers to carry out activities that are strictly necessary for the operation or delivery of the Service.

### Functionality

Short.io uses Trackers to enable basic interactions and functionalities, allowing Users to access selected features of the Service and facilitating the User's communication with the Owner.

#### Trackers managed by third parties

* ### Canny
    
    We display changelog from this service
    
* ### Facebook Authentication (Meta Platforms, Inc.)
    
    Facebook Authentication is a registration and authentication service provided by Meta Platforms, Inc. and is connected to the Facebook social network.
    
    Personal Data processed: Trackers and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
    
    Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/help/405977429438260).
    
    Storage duration:
    
    * \_fbp: 3 months
    * fbssls\_\*: duration of the session

### Measurement

Short.io uses Trackers to measure traffic and analyse User behaviour to improve the Service.

#### Trackers managed by third parties

* ### Hotjar Heat Maps & Recordings (Hotjar Ltd.)
    
    Hotjar is a session recording and heat mapping service provided by Hotjar Ltd.  
    Hotjar honors generic „Do Not Track” headers. This means the browser can tell its script not to collect any of the User's data. This is a setting that is available in all major browsers. Find Hotjar’s [opt-out information here](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out).
    
    Personal Data processed: Cookies, Usage Data and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
    
    Place of processing: Malta – [Privacy Policy](https://www.hotjar.com/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out).
    
    Storage duration:
    
    * \_hjAbsoluteSessionInProgress: 30 minutes
    * \_hjCachedUserAttributes: duration of the session
    * \_hjClosedSurveyInvites: 1 year
    * \_hjDonePolls: 1 year
    * \_hjFirstSeen: duration of the session
    * \_hjIncludedInSessionSample: 30 minutes
    * \_hjLocalStorageTest: duration of the session
    * \_hjLocalStorageTest: duration of the session
    * \_hjMinimizedPolls: 1 year
    * \_hjSession\*: 30 minutes
    * \_hjSessionRejected: duration of the session
    * \_hjSessionResumed: duration of the session
    * \_hjSessionTooLarge: 1 hour
    * \_hjSessionUser\*: 1 year
    * \_hjSessionUser\_\*: 2 years
    * \_hjShownFeedbackMessage: 1 year
    * \_hjTLDTest: duration of the session
    * \_hjUserAttributesHash: duration of the session
    * \_hjViewportId: duration of the session
    * \_hjid: 1 year
    
* ### Google Analytics 4
    
    Google Analytics 4 is a web analysis service provided by Google LLC or by Google Ireland Limited, depending on how the Owner manages the Data processing, (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of short.io, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.  
    Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.  
    In Google Analytics 4, IP addresses are used at collection time and then discarded before Data is logged in any data center or server. Users can learn more by consulting [Google’s official documentation](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/12017362?hl=en&ref_topic=2919631).
    
    In order to understand Google's use of Data, consult [Google's partner policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).
    
    Personal Data processed: number of Users, session statistics, Trackers and Usage Data.
    
    Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://business.safety.google/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en); Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://business.safety.google/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).
    
    Storage duration:
    
    * \_ga: 2 years
    * \_ga\_\*: 2 years

### Marketing

Short.io uses Trackers to deliver personalized ads or marketing content, and to measure their performance.

#### Trackers managed by third parties

* ### Google Ads Remarketing (Google Inc.)
    
    Google Ads Remarketing is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Google LLC or by Google Ireland Limited, depending on how the Owner manages the Data processing, that connects the activity of short.io with the Google Ads advertising network and the DoubleClick Cookie.
    
    Users can opt out of Google's use of cookies for ads personalization by visiting Google's [Ads Settings](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated).
    
    Personal Data processed: Cookies and Usage Data.
    
    Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout).
    
    Storage duration:
    
    * Conversion: 3 months
    * DSID: 14 days
    * FCNEC: 1 year
    * FLC: 10 seconds
    * FPAU: 3 months
    * FPGCLAW: 3 months
    * FPGCLDC: 3 months
    * FPGCLGB: 3 months
    * GCL\_AW\_P: 3 months
    * GED\_PLAYLIST\_ACTIVITY: duration of the session
    * IDE: 2 years
    * NID: 6 months
    * RUL: 1 year
    * \_\_gads: 2 years
    * \_\_gpi: 2 years
    * \_\_gpi\_optout: 2 years
    * \_\_gsas: 2 years
    * \_gac\_: 3 months
    * \_gac\_gb\_: 3 months
    * \_gcl\_ag: 3 months
    * \_gcl\_au: 3 months
    * \_gcl\_aw: 3 months
    * \_gcl\_dc: 3 months
    * \_gcl\_gb: 3 months
    * \_gcl\_gf: 3 months
    * \_gcl\_gs: 3 months
    * \_gcl\_ha: 3 months
    * ar\_debug: 3 months
    * id: 2 years
    * receive-cookie-deprecation: 6 months
    * test\_cookie: 15 minutes
    
* ### Google Ads conversion tracking (Google Inc.)
    
    Google Ads conversion tracking is an analytics service provided by Google LLC or by Google Ireland Limited, depending on how the Owner manages the Data processing, that connects data from the Google Ads advertising network with actions performed on short.io.
    
    Personal Data processed: Trackers and Usage Data.
    
    Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).
    
    Storage duration:
    
    * IDE: 2 years
    * test\_cookie: 15 minutes
    
* ### Intercom (Intercom Inc.)
    
    Intercom is a User database management service provided by Intercom Inc. Intercom can also be used as a medium for communications, either through email, or through messages within short.io.
    
    Personal Data processed: Cookies, email address, Usage Data and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
    
    Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#privacy).
    
    Storage duration:
    
    * intercom-id-\*: 10 months
    * intercom-session-\*: 7 days
    * intercom-test: indefinite

### How to manage preferences and provide or withdraw consent on short.io

Whenever the use of Trackers is based on consent, users can provide or withdraw such consent by setting or updating their preferences via the relevant privacy choices panel available on short.io.

With regard to any third-party Trackers, Users can manage their preferences via the related opt-out link (where provided), by using the means indicated in the third party's privacy policy, or by contacting the third party.

#### How to control or delete Cookies and similar technologies via your device settings

Users may use their own browser settings to:

* See what Cookies or other similar technologies have been set on the device;
* Block Cookies or similar technologies;
* Clear Cookies or similar technologies from the browser.

The browser settings, however, do not allow granular control of consent by category.

Users can, for example, find information about how to manage Cookies in the most commonly used browsers at the following addresses:

Users may also manage certain categories of Trackers used on mobile apps by opting out through relevant device settings such as the device advertising settings for mobile devices, or tracking settings in general (Users may open the device settings and look for the relevant setting).

#### How to opt out of interest-based advertising

Notwithstanding the above, Users may follow the instructions provided by [YourOnlineChoices](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) (EU and UK), the [Network Advertising Initiative](https://thenai.org/about-online-advertising/) (US) and the [Digital Advertising Alliance](https://www.aboutads.info/consumers/) (US), [DAAC](https://youradchoices.ca/understanding-online-advertising/) (Canada), [DDAI](http://www.ddai.info/optout) (Japan) or other similar services. Such initiatives allow Users to select their tracking preferences for most of the advertising tools. The Owner thus recommends that Users make use of these resources in addition to the information provided in this document.

The Digital Advertising Alliance offers an application called [AppChoices](https://youradchoices.com/appchoices) that helps Users to control interest-based advertising on mobile apps.

#### Consequences of denying the use of Trackers

Users are free to decide whether or not to allow the use of Trackers. However, please note that Trackers help short.io to provide a better experience and advanced functionalities to Users (in line with the purposes outlined in this document). Therefore, if the User chooses to block the use of Trackers, the Owner may be unable to provide related features.

### Owner and Data Controller

Short.cm

**Owner contact email:** support@short.io

Since the use of third-party Trackers through short.io cannot be fully controlled by the Owner, any specific references to third-party Trackers are to be considered indicative. In order to obtain complete information, Users are kindly requested to consult the privacy policies of the respective third-party services listed in this document.

Given the objective complexity surrounding tracking technologies, Users are encouraged to contact the Owner should they wish to receive any further information on the use of such technologies by short.io.

### Definitions and legal references

#### Personal Data (or Data)

Any information that directly, indirectly, or in connection with other information — including a personal identification number — allows for the identification or identifiability of a natural person.

#### Usage Data

Information collected automatically through short.io (or third-party services employed in short.io), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use short.io, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server's answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User's IT environment.

#### User

The individual using short.io who, unless otherwise specified, coincides with the Data Subject.

#### Data Subject

The natural person to whom the Personal Data refers.

#### Data Processor (or Processor)

The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which processes Personal Data on behalf of the Controller, as described in this privacy policy.

#### Data Controller (or Owner)

The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the processing of Personal Data, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of short.io. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of short.io.

#### short.io (or this Application)

The means by which the Personal Data of the User is collected and processed.

#### Service

The service provided by short.io as described in the relative terms (if available) and on this site/application.

#### European Union (or EU)

Unless otherwise specified, all references made within this document to the European Union include all current member states to the European Union and the European Economic Area.

#### Cookie

Cookies are Trackers consisting of small sets of data stored in the User's browser.

#### Tracker

Tracker indicates any technology - e.g Cookies, unique identifiers, web beacons, embedded scripts, e-tags and fingerprinting - that enables the tracking of Users, for example by accessing or storing information on the User’s device.

* * *

#### Legal information

This privacy policy relates solely to short.io, if not stated otherwise within this document.

Latest update: December 03, 2024

Version: 3

Withdraw consent

Product

Resources

About us

* Contact Us

Community

Choose a Language:

© Copyright 2015-2024 Short.cm Inc. All Rights Reserved. [Terms & Conditions](https://short.io/terms) [Privacy Policy and GDPR](https://short.io/privacy)

Do you want to visit 上海索特艾欧科技有限公司 website?
